paytrust.com 2005-12-08

# Paytrust : Paytrust Privacy and Security Guarantee

How do we protect your personal information? 

We work to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration by using industry-recognized security safeguards. When you transmit your information to us, it is protected by: 

  * A secure Internet connection using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. 
  * Encryption during transmission using 40-bit or 128-bit encryption (whichever your browser supports) to make your information unreadable as it passes over the Internet. 

Tell me more about your security practices. 

What information do we collect and how do we use it?    
  
When you use our online services, we collect the following types of information: 

  * **Contact Information** that you provide, such as your name, address, phone, e-mail address as part of the enrollment process. We use this information in the event we need to contact you about the Paytrust service. We may also use your contact information together with your purchase history, to send you occasional promotional or marketing communications that may be of interest to you or to invite you to participate in service-related surveys. You may control the use of your contact information for promotional, marketing, or survey-related communications by specifying your contact preferences. 
  * **Verification Information** such as your date of birth or social security number to confirm your identity at the time of enrollment. To protect access to your account, we will also ask you to verify your identity in the event you contact Customer Support for assistance with your account. This information will only be used to verify critical information about you, including your contact information, in relation to your Paytrust account. 
  * **Bank and Payee Information** such as bank account, routing number, and payee information is used to process payments on your behalf from your account. This information is not used for any other purpose. 
  * **Technical Information** such as your IP address, browser type or version, pages viewed, and links selected to help us evaluate web site usage. This information helps us to determine areas of our Web sites that are most helpful to our customers and what areas may need improvement. We use cookies to help us track site usage. We also use cookies to make your visit to our Web site easier by recognizing you when you return or by customizing your Web site experience. Tell me more about the Web technologies that you use. 
  * **Other Information Sources.** We may use sources outside of Intuit to verify or supplement the information you give us. For example, we may confirm or update your mailing address using directories or through change of address notifications. This helps us to ensure that your information is up-to-date. 
  * **Closed or Inactive Accounts.** If you are a former customer with a closed or inactive account, we treat your information in the same manner that we treat information about our current customers. 

Tell me more about services on this site. 

When do we share your information? 

We understand that you are entrusting us with your personal information. **That's why we don't sell, rent, or share any of the personal information you provide to us with companies outside of Intuit for their own promotional or marketing use.** There are occasions, however, where we must share your information to provide you with the services you requested or for legal reasons. Descriptions of when we share and whom we may share your information with are provided below. 

  * **With Service Providers.** In some cases, we use third party service providers to provide a product you order, to fulfill a service you request, or to market one of our products or services. These service providers act on our behalf. For example, we may use service providers to provide customer support or to host our Web sites. Service providers are strictly prohibited from using your information for their own purposes. Our contracts only allow service providers to use the personal information we disclose to them to provide you the service you have requested. 
  * **With Partners.** We have limited relationships with third party business partners to offer you products or services that we believe you may find beneficial. Some of these are co-branded products or services. We clearly identify partner services and sites, so you will know who is receiving your information. When you request any of these partner products or services, you are permitting us to provide your personal information to the partner to fulfill your request. 

We may also offer links to partner or other third party Web sites. We do not control the privacy or security practices used on these sites. Before you provide your personal information to these third parties, we recommend that you review their privacy policies to learn more about how they may use your information. 

  * **Within Intuit, including among our subsidiaries.** We may share your contact information, and the types of products and services you have purchased from us, among Intuit and our subsidiaries (companies that are part of our corporate family through Intuit ownership or control). **We do not share your verification, bank or payee information with subsidiaries.**
  * **Sale of a business.** Should we sell, merge, or transfer any part of our business, part of the sale may include your personal information. If so, you will have the opportunity to ask not to receive promotional information following any change of control. 
  * **For legal reasons.** In some cases we may be required to disclose certain information to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authorities, comply with a legal process, such as a court order, subpoena, search warrant, law enforcement request, or as otherwise permitted by law to comply with legal requirements. 

Can I opt-out of receiving future communication? 

We may use your contact information to tell you about other products we think might interest you. However, if you don't want us to contact you for promotional purposes, you can tell us when you provide the information. You may also specify your contact preferences by visiting our Privacy Web site. Your contact preferences only apply to marketing contact. We may need to communicate with you regarding the usability of your product or critical messages relating to your service or software (such as service messages, subscription renewal notices, critical notices, or legally mandated notices). 

How do I update my contact information? 

You can update or correct your contact information relating to your Paytrust account by: 

  * Visiting www.Paytrust.com   
Sign in to the Bill Center and click the Profile button. Then click the Personal Information link and edit your information as needed. 
  * Contacting Paytrust Customer Support at 1-800-PAYTRUST (729-8787) 
  * Sending a request via fax: 1-877-329-7298 
  * Sending a request via US mail to the following postal address:   
      Paytrust   
      P.O. Box 7235   
      Sioux Falls, SD 57117-7235 

Will I be notified of changes to your privacy practices? 

If we make material changes to any of our privacy policies or practices regarding personal information we will update our statement and post a notice on our site 30 days before they take effect. 

As required by law, if you are a current customer, we provide you with notice of our privacy practices annually. We may choose to provide this annual notice by postal mail, e-mail, or by posting it on our Web site. 

Who can I contact with a privacy question? 

If you have privacy-related questions that are not addressed here, please contact the [Privacy Team](https://privacy.intuit.com/cpi/do/comments) or write us at: Privacy Team, Intuit Inc, 2800 East Commerce Center Place, Tucson, AZ 85706. 

Back to Top

More about how we protect your information 

We protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information by using industry-recognized security safeguards such as firewalls, coupled with carefully developed security procedures to protect your information from loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration. 

Our employees are trained and required to safeguard your information and, using physical, electronic and procedural safeguards, we restrict access to personal information to those employees and agents for business purposes only. Additionally, we use internal and external resources to review the adequacy of our security procedures. 

Back

More about services offered on the Paytrust.com site 

**Paytrust Enrollment.** The enrollment page is hosted by Metavante Payment Services, LLC on behalf of Intuit. Metavante is not permitted to use your information for any other purpose than to provide you the Paytrust services you are requesting. 

**Receiving Bills Online.** If you choose to receive bills online, your payees will be notified to send your bills, either electronically or by mail, to the Paytrust processing center. The information you provide to Paytrust for these services, as well as your bills and billing information, is stored on Paytrust servers using industry-recognized security safeguards. Bills are presented to you online within your password protected Paytrust Service. 

  * **Electronic Billing Statements.**
    * For some payees, Paytrust can retrieve an electronic version of your bill directly from your payee's Web site. To receive bills this way, you provide Paytrust with the user names and passwords for your payee Web sites. Paytrust downloads and saves an HTML or PDF representation of your bill. 
    * You may also have some payees send your electronic billing data directly to Paytrust. Paytrust verifies your payee account information with your payee and then instructs your payee to either display your bill information or transmit your bill information to Paytrust. 
  * **Paper Billing Statements.** For payees from whom we do not receive billing data electronically, you may have your paper bills mailed to Paytrust. Your paper bills are scanned into the Paytrust system. Scanned bills are shredded prior to being discarded. 

**SmartBalance™.** SmartBalance is a feature that combines your online bank account activity with your bill payment record so you have the most updated and accurate picture of your bank balance. If you request, Paytrust will store your online bank accounts' User IDs so that you don't need to enter them each time you update SmartBalance. You must enter your password(s) each time you update SmartBalance. To provide this service, Paytrust stores your transaction information for your bank account - who was paid, how much was paid and what the check number was used. Available balance is also stored for calculating the SmartBalance. 

SmartBalance is a trademark of Metavante Corporation. 

Back

More about how we use Web technologies 

Like many Web sites, we use a variety of technologies on our Web site. Among these are cookies, which are pieces of information that our Web sites provide to your browser. Cookies allow us to track overall site usage and determine areas users prefer. Cookies also allow us to customize your visit to our Web site by recognizing you when you return. You can choose to decline cookies while at our Web site, however, this may limit your ability to access certain areas of the Web site. Most browsers accept and maintain cookies by default. Check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preference. 

When we track activity on this or other Intuit Web sites, we collect information such as your IP address, browser type and version, and pages you view. We also keep track of how you got to our site and any links you click on to leave our site. We do not track URLs that you type into your browser, nor do we track you across the Internet once your leave our sites. We use your Web site activity to assist you by reducing the need to re-enter your data and to help us resolve technical support issues. We may also use this information to offer you a personalized Web experience and to tailor our offerings to you. Remember, you control whether you receive Intuit promotional materials. 

We may access and set cookies using Web beacons, also known as single-pixel GIFs which are invisible graphical images. These Web beacons tell us useful information regarding our site such as which pages users access. When we send you e-mails, we may include a single-pixel GIF to determine the number of people who open our e-mails. When you click on a link in an e-mail, we record this individual response to allow us to customize our offerings to you. 

Advertising networks that serve ads on our Web site may assign a different cookie to you. The information collected is anonymous and is not linked to your personal information. These cookies may be used to select which ads you see and determine the effectiveness of this advertising. You may choose to decline cookies from third-party ad servers, which Intuit does not control. If you would like to know more about this practice and your choices about not having this information used by third-party ad servers, please click here. 

To provide you with a seamless experience, we may occasionally use framing. Though your browser may indicate you are at Paytrust.com, you may be on a partner's site. To determine which site you are on, right-click on the page and then select "properties." Mac users should press the control key, and click their mouse on the site and then look at "View Source." 

Back

Last Updated : July 24, 2005
